<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Community | Tower of Power]]></title>
  <link href="http://dcousineau.github.com/blog/categories/community/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dcousineau.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-03T11:13:31-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://dcousineau.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel Cousineau]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Make The Most Of ZendCon]]></title>
    <link href="http://dcousineau.github.com/blog/2009/10/15/make-the-most-of-zendcon/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-15T19:43:12-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dcousineau.github.com/blog/2009/10/15/make-the-most-of-zendcon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I felt like I should take a break from finishing up my <a href="/blog/2009/10/13/solve-a-sliding-puzzle-with-javascript-and-your-ai-course-part-1/">multi-part javascript series</a> to rehash some points being made recently by <a href="http://caseysoftware.com/blog/so-its-your-first-conference">Keith Casey</a> and <a href="http://blog.phpdeveloper.org/?p=221">Chris Cornutt</a> about making the most of your N-th conference (and in particular, ZendCon).</p>

<p>My first ever professional conference (ignoring BarCamps) was last year's ZendCon. I showed up in Santa Clara not knowing anyone except for a few brief appearances on #phpc (freenode).</p>

<p>What made ZendCon absolutely enjoyable was indeed what everyone is suggesting to you: the hallway track.</p>

<p>I could have easily attended sessions then hid in my room until the next day, yet I chose to go out to the social events and thanks to that decision, ZendCon '08 remains currently one of my fondest memories.</p>

<p>It's one thing to sit down and listen to talks from famous PHP developers, those that I read about all the time (or read their books in many cases). It's a whole other beast to find yourself sharing a beer with them in some random "English Pub" while getting your ass kicked at trivia (I still have the beer glasses that were given to me by the real winners).</p>

<p>And these events didn't happen because I'm some modest uber-genius (I am by no means modest), I'm famous, or even particularly well respected ("He's not stupid" is as gracious as a comment as I could want in a programming community).</p>

<p>They happened because someone yelled "Pub Crawl!" and, dammit, I was there.</p>

<p>They happened because I struck up conversations with random people.</p>

<p>They happened because I got in religious flame wars with random people. (Ask me about the time, thought not at ZendCon, where I launched into a tirade against CakePHP with who I later found out was the founder of CakePHP)</p>

<p>As it has been reiterated time and time again, this conference is not really about the sessions (it's a success if there's just 1 talk that you go to). It's about the people you meet and the friendships you foster.</p>

<p>In summation, I have a list of goals for you, my loyal readers that are attending ZendCon:</p>

<ol>
<li>Start a conversation with a random person in a hallway</li>
<li>Find and say hi to an author of one your PHP books. Tell them how awesome the book has been</li>
<li>Attend at least 1 UnCon session</li>
<li>Attend at least 1 post-session social (keep track on Twitter and ask your fellow attendees for info)</li>
<li>Find me and introduce yourself</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ZendCon08 Wrapup]]></title>
    <link href="http://dcousineau.github.com/blog/2008/09/22/zendcon08-wrapup/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-22T11:49:42-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dcousineau.github.com/blog/2008/09/22/zendcon08-wrapup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I kinda had a thing going about blogging during ZendCon but lost it, so I might as well just do a single day wrap up.</p>

<p>So ZendCon turned out to be completely worth it, even if only for the chance to meet in person a lot of the core PHP community and then drink semi-copiously with them.</p>

<p>The talks were good, though most of them were either more basic than I would have liked or really indepth (/me thinks back to Sara's PHP Extension Writing talk, though that was more "few php developers gets this deep" than indepth/complicated).</p>

<p>The uncon was nice, which of course I'd like it given my love for barcamps, refreshes, and generally community driven and adhoc events.</p>

<p>The Yahoo party started out awkward given that one expects an open bar after paying $500+ for tickets to a conference, however from what I gathered it really wasn't so much Yahoo's fault more the hotel's. I won the raffle for the "Day with Rasmus" prize and felt bad 'cause when one of the Yahoo girls came to me and to have me verify my information, I told them my email (which was a gmail account) was correct but if they still have trouble to just google my first and last name since I dominate the first page for my name.</p>

<p>My only problem with ZendCon is that it ended...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ZendCon08 Day 1 Wrap Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://dcousineau.github.com/blog/2008/09/17/zendcon08-day-1-wrap-up/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-17T12:52:40-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dcousineau.github.com/blog/2008/09/17/zendcon08-day-1-wrap-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Turned out to be a fairly exciting day. I woke up late wondering why my alarms didn't go off, just barely got to lunch and regretted missing <a href="http://www.jpipes.com/index.php">Jay Pipes</a>' talk.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.libssh2.org/">Sara Golemon</a> gave an interesting introduction to PHP extension writing. I bow to her vastly superior C-fu.</p>

<p>I <a href="/blog/2008/09/16/zendcon-day-1-pecl-picks/">already</a> <a href="/blog/2008/09/16/zendcon08-day-1-the-knight-rider-methodology-to-software-development/">discussed</a> a few talks that I went to yesterday as well.</p>

<p>Ended the night doing a pub crawl with some people (hung out with Jay Pipes at the end which is what caused me to regret missing his talk).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ZendCon08 Day 1 - The Knight Rider Methodology to Software Development]]></title>
    <link href="http://dcousineau.github.com/blog/2008/09/16/zendcon08-day-1-the-knight-rider-methodology-to-software-development/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-16T11:24:08-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dcousineau.github.com/blog/2008/09/16/zendcon08-day-1-the-knight-rider-methodology-to-software-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://eliw.com/">Eli White</a> gave a talk called <a href="http://eliw.com/conference/zendcon-2008-KnightRider.pdf">"The Knight Rider Methodology to Software Development"</a>.</p>

<p>He compares software development methodologies to the old TV show <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knight_Rider">Knight Rider</a>, in that the main character, Michael Knight, was average and ordinary except for the fact that he had an applicable toolset for what he needed to do (KITT).</p>

<p>Eli talks about how while locking yourself into a programming language (company wise) is okay in that when you hire you know that the candidate has to know at lease a finite number of languages. But you shouldn't force employees to use locked in tools. If they like their own editor debugger combo, let them use it because they will be faster, the code will still work the same.</p>

<p>He goes over different tools you'll use for different purposes. Editors, debuggers, load testers, etc.</p>

<p>The movie clips are great, which you unfortunately don't get on the downloadable presentation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ZendCon08 Day 1 - PECL Picks]]></title>
    <link href="http://dcousineau.github.com/blog/2008/09/16/zendcon-day-1-pecl-picks/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-16T10:03:44-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dcousineau.github.com/blog/2008/09/16/zendcon-day-1-pecl-picks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://elizabethmariesmith.com/">Elizabeth Smith</a> discussed to a really interesting PECL extension, <a href="http://pecl.php.net/package/pecl_http">pecl_http</a>. I can do request pooling!</p>

<p>She also discussed <a href="http://pecl.php.net/package/pdo_user">pdo_user</a> that allows you to create PDO drivers in userland (PHP).</p>

<p>Good overview on PECL packages. It makes me sad that they have really cool extensions like the operator overload extension and I can use them because I have to worry about install bases of other users :( Damned shared hosts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
